Guide to the New-York Historical Society Pictorial Archive 1804-2009 (bulk 1900s-1970s) NYHS-RG 5
New-York Historical Society
- Series XI. Negatives, circa 1900-1990s; 11.38 Linear feet
  Each negative (or 35 mm roll) has a unique control number, which is noted on the envelope housing the negative. Within each box, the negatives are arranged in control number order. This number was often written on the back of a related print thereby linking the print and negative. Accordingly, to facilitate finding a particular negative regardless of format or size, the container list is arranged in control number order. Each entry in the container list indicates a range of control numbers, the format and size of the negatives common to the range (which also indicates the size of the box they are in), and the box number in which the negative will be found.
  There is not necessarily a negative for every control number in the ranges shown in the container list. Gaps are very common because of the designation of a control number to a negative other than one in the institutional archive, lost or destroyed negatives, or other reason. Because of the gaps, there is often a sharp discrepancy between the actual number of negatives and the number implied by the range. To correct for this, each entry in the container list includes a note concerning the subject matter of the negatives in the range with a parenthetical indicator of the approximate number of actual negatives, for example: "Exhibitions: Early American Toys (4)."
  - Negative #14. Film, 8x10, 1944 (Box 29, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Microfilm storage stacks
  - Negative #106-109. Glass, 8x10, Undated (Box 41, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Central Park West exterior (1), interior (1).
  - Negative #175-178. Film, 8x10, 1947-1948 (Box 29, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Golden Anniversary of Greater New York (1); Gold Fever: California Gold Rush (1)
  - Negative #197-209. Glass, 8x10, Undated (Box 41, Envelope -)
    Buildings: 2nd Avenue exterior (1), interior (12).
  - Negative #198. Film, 5x7, Undated (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Building: Copy of 2nd Avenue interior glass negative #198.
  - Negative #237-269. Film, 8x10, 1947-1948 (Box 29, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Gold Fever: California Gold Rush (1); Recent Accessions (1); Up From the Cradle (1)
  - Negative #402-408. Glass, 8x10, 1917 (Box 41, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Central Park West interior (3).
  - Negative #561-562. Film, 8x10, Undated (Box 29, Envelope -)
    Engraving: Distinguished Americans at N-YHS (2)
  - Negative #585-599. Glass, 8x10, 1919, Undated (Box 41, Envelope -)
    Buildings: 2nd Avenue exterior (1); Lithograph of Remsen Building (1); Woodcut of Stuyvesant Institute Building (1).
  - Negative #617-631. Film, 8x10, 1948, Undated (Box 29, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Gold Fever: California Gold Rush (2); U.S. Navy (1)
  - Negative #646-647. Glass, 5x7, Before 1937 (Box 43, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Central Park West exterior (2).
  - Negative #652-670. Film, 8x10, 1948 (Box 29, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Gold Fever: California Gold Rush (7)
  - Negative #674. Glass, 8x10, circa 1920 (Box 41, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Central Park West exterior (1).
  - Negative #675-684. Film, 8x10, 1948, Undated (Box 29, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Gold Fever: California Gold Rush (3); Audubon Room (1)
  - Negative #900. Film, 5x7, Undated (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Exhibition: Presidential Campaigns of 19th Century (1).
  - Negative #909-910. Glass, 8x10, 1933 (Box 41, Envelope -)
    Exhibition: Nash-Hoffman American household collection (2).
  - Negative #932-2056. Film, 8x10, 1941-1951, Undated (Box 29, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions and Objects: Prentis Collection (9); Poster for autograph manuscripts (1); Benjamin Franklin: American Patriot (2); Tiffany Whistle (1); Erie Canal (5); Belknap genealogy (2); Newspapers (3); Galleries (8); Early American Children's Books (1)
  - Negative #2180-2199. Film, 5x7, 1950, Undated (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Objects: Memorial to S.H.P. Pell (1). Object/Staff: Publicity photo of Fire Department object.
  - Negative #2338-2344. Glass, 8x10, circa 1933 (Box 41, Envelope -)
    Buildings: 4 West 77th Street / Annex 2, exterior (1), ship exhibition (1).
  - Negative #2406-2514. Film, 8x10, 1951-1952 (Box 29, Envelope -)
    Outside signage (2); Poster for exhibition Country Houses on Manhattan Island (1).
  - Negative #2515-2517. Glass, 8x10, 1933 (Box 41, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Central Park West interior (3), basement exhibition hall with Nash-Hoffman American households and Fire Department objects.
  - Negative #2710-3341. Film, 8x10, 1933-1952 (Box 29, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Albert Gallatin (5); Prentis (7); Recent Accessions (4); St. Nicholas Came to New York (1); Visit from St. Nicholas (1); Military Academy (3); Newspapers (5); Country Houses (6); Meet Mr. Lincoln (1); Valentines (1); GI's in 7 Wars (4); Early American Toys (5); New York views in 4 West 77th St. Annex (1). Galleries & Rooms (5). Staff (2).
  - Negative #3482-3692. Film, 5x7, 1951, Undated (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Galleries (4), including Period Rooms.
  - Negative #3810-3828. Film, 8x10, 1934-1936 (Box 30, Envelope -)
    Gallery (1). Annex 1/#5 West 76th St. (1) and Annex 2/#4 West 77th St. (1). Lots at Central Park West and West 76th and 77th streets (2).
  - Negative #4112. Film, 5x7, circa 1900? (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Buildings: 2nd Avenue, exterior (1).
  - Negative #4113-4151. Glass, 8x10, [1903], 1905-1906 (Box 42, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Central Park West cornerstone laying (6); construction of building's "central portion" (33).
  - Negative #4247. Film, 5x7, 1904 (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Objects: N-YHS Centennial medal (1).
  - Negative #4432-4445. Film, 8x10, 1936-1951 (Box 30, Envelope -)
    Galleries (1). Object (1). Exhibition: Period Rooms/Prentis? (8).
  - Negative #4469. Film, 5x7, Undated (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Buildings: 1887 view of future N-YHS Central Park West site (1).
  - Negative #4478. Film, 8x10, 1942 (Box 30, Envelope -)
    Exhibition: Meet Mr. Lincoln (1).
  - Negative #4583-4586. Film, 5x7, 1950 (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Early American Toys (4).
  - Negative #4626. Film, 8x10, 1941 (Box 30, Envelope -)
    Port of New York Room (1)
  - Negative #4800-5103. Film, 5x7, 1950, 1954 (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Belknap Collection (1); N-YHS Sesquicentennial Medal (3). Programs & Events: Pianist Lonny Epstein (3).
  - Negative #5326-5420. Film, 8x10, 1937, 1952 (Box 30, Envelope -)
    Nadelman Museum gallery prior to removal (1). Country Houses signage (1). Buildings construction (3)
  - Negative #5421. Film, 5x7, 1938 (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Buildings: Townhouses on West 76th Sreet (1).
  - Negative #6113-6288. Film, 8x10, 1938, 1952-1953 (Box 30, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Hat in the Ring (4); Great Lake Steamboats (2). Galleries (5).
  - Negative #6441. Film, 5x7, 1955 (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Staff: Bella Landauer at N-YHS desk.
  - Negative #6482-6877. Film, 8x10, 1938-1953, Undated (Box 30, Envelope -)
    Galleries and Rooms (36). Exhibitions: St. Nicholas Came to New York (1); Taylor collection of glass (1); Fire Department (1); Wings Over the Pacific: Army Air Forces (3); Circus Time signage (1). Events (2). Building views (2).
  - Negative #7113-8019. Film, 8x10, 1939-1953, Undated (Box 31, Envelope -)
    Galleries and Rooms (45). Building exteriors (4). Exhibitions: Miniatures (9); Meet Mr. Lincoln (1); Story of Photography in America (4); Wings Over the Pacific: Army Air Forces (2); 135th Anniversary (9); Dolls & Toys of Yesterday (1). Events & Programs (14). Egyptian collection at Brooklyn Museum (9). Staff (1).
  - Negative #8026-8029. Film, 5x7, circa 1940? (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Objects: Egyptian Collection displayed at Brooklyn Museum (4).
  - Negative #8030-8109. Film, 8x10, 1940, 1953, Undated (Box 31, Envelope -)
    Programs and Events (5). Exhibitions: Dolls & Toys of Yesterday (11). Galleries and Rooms (1).
  - Negative #8117-8330. Film, 8x10, 1940, 1953, Undated (Box 32, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Colt Revolver (2). Building/2nd Ave (1). Exhibitions: Dolls & Toys of Yesterday (6); John Wesley Jarvis (2); Costume Collection (1). Galleries and Rooms (9).
  - Negative #8389-8394. Film, 5x7, 1950 (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Staff Christmas Parties (6).
  - Negative #8426-8451. Film, 8x10, 1940 (Box 32, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Peter Stuyvesant (1); John Paul Jones (1).
  - Negative #8703-8849. Film, 5x7, 1939, Undated (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Presidential Campaigns of the 19th Century (1). Buildings: 2nd Avenue, exterior (1), interior (9). Staff: Board of Trustees, 1939 (1).
  - Negative #8928-8933. Film, 8x10, 1940 (Box 32, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Presidential Campaigns (3); Military Drafts (2); Christmas Greetings (1).
  - Negative #8978-8984. Film, 5x7, 1940 (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Emma Thursby Memorial (7).
  - Negative #8988-16100. Film, 8x10, 1940, 1949-1950, Undated (Box 32, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Military Drafts (1); Emma Thursby (2); Confederate States of America (4); New York in Watercolor (1); Recent Accessions (1); Bookplates (7). Building exterior (6). Galleries and Rooms (4). Programs & Events (2). High School Loan Exhibition: New York from Meadow to Metropolis (8). Home Industry Series (8). Signage (7).
  - Negative #16264-16606. Film, 5x7, 1948-1949 (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Staff, staff events, trustees (9). Events: Presentation of Smith medical papyrus to New York Academy of Medicine (1).
  - Negative #18501-18507. Film, 8x10, 1939-1940 (Box 32, Envelope -)
    Winter scenes of Central Park taken from N-YHS roof (7).
  - Negative #18812. Film, 5x7, Undated (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Objects: Unidentified artwork (1).
  - Negative #18839-18981. Film, 8x10, 1941 (Box 32, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Gerardus Boyce (1); Horace Greeley (2); How Early America Lived (2); American Scenes & Events on Textiles (5).
  - Negative #20494. Glass, 5x7, Undated (Box 43, Envelope -)
    Object: Portrait of John Abeel (2).
  - Negative #20495-20496. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 47, Envelope -)
    Objects: Engraving of John Quincy Adams (1); The Arsenal in Central Park (1).
  - Negative #20497. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 43, Envelope -)
    Object: Portrait of Henry Abbott (object 1863.10) (2).
  - Negative #20498. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 47, Envelope -)
    Objects: N-YHS Bushnell Medal (2).
  - Negative #20499. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 43, Envelope -)
    Object: Portrait of Anthony Bleecker (2).
  - Negative #20500. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 47, Envelope -)
    Objects: Egyptian Mummified Bull (2).
  - Negative #20501. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 43, Envelope -)
    Objects: Portrait of Luther Bradish (2); Portrait of Egbert Benson (2); Tombstone of William Bradford (2).
  - Negative #20504. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 47, Envelope -)
    Objects: William Bradford tablets (1).
  - Negative #20506-20507. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 43, Envelope -)
    Buildings: 2nd Avenue interior (2). Object: Portrait of Samuel Bayard (1).
  - Negative #20508-20509. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 47, Envelope -)
    Objects: Engraving of George Bancroft (1); Engraving of the Church of the Messiah (1).
  - Negative #20510-20511. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 44, Envelope -)
    Objects: Andrea Mantegna Crucifixion (object 1867.45) (2); Rembrandt Combat of Cavalry (object 1882.103) (2).
  - Negative #20512-20515. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 47, Envelope -)
    Objects: Illustration of Middle Dutch Church (1); Illustration of Franklin Square (1); Portrait of DeWitt Clinton (2); Portrait of Thomas De Witt (1).
  - Negative #20516-20517. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 44, Envelope -)
    Objects: Bust of Louis Durr (1); Engraving of Frederic DePeyster (2).
  - Negative #20518-20519. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 47, Envelope -)
    Objects: Egyptian collection jewelry (4).
  - Negative #20520-20521. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 44, Envelope -)
    Objects: Engraving of Benjamin A. Fields (2); Iron railing from Federal Hall.
  - Negative #20526-50528. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 47, Envelope -)
    Objects: Portrait of Hamilton Fish (1); Fort George items (2).
  - Negative #20529. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 44, Envelope -)
    Objects: Engraving of Albert Gallatin (2).
  - Negative #20530. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 47, Envelope -)
    Objects: Lithograph of Government House (1).
  - Negative #20531. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 44, Envelope -)
    Objects: Arny de Voys The Happy Burgher (object 1882.92) (2).
  - Negative #20532. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 48, Envelope -)
    Object: Portrait of Eugene A. Hoffman (2).
  - Negative #20533. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 44, Envelope -)
    Objects: Portrait of Eugene A. Hoffman (object 1902.5) (2).
  - Negative #20534-20535. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 48, Envelope -)
    Objects: Portrait of David Hosack (1); Portrait of Francis Lister Hawks (1).
  - Negative #20536-20539. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 45, Envelope -)
    Objects: Batholome Esteban Murillo Immaculate Conception (object 1882.2) (2); Velazquez Infanta Margarita of Spain (2); Bust of Peter A. Jay (2); Portrait of John A. King (2).
  - Negative #20540-20543. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 48, Envelope -)
    Objects: Portrait of John A. King (2); Portrait of James Kent (1); Portrait of Morgan Lewis (1).
  - Negative #20544-20545. Glass, 5x7, 1904, Undated (Box 45, Envelope -)
    Objects: Portrait of James Lenox (2); Portrait of William Linn (2).
  - Negative #20546. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 48, Envelope -)
    Object: Broadside for a grand national lottery in 1816 (2).
  - Negative #20549-20554. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 45, Envelope -)
    Objects: Engraving of Samuel Miller (1); Engraving of John M. Mason (2); Chair of Marie Antoinette (object 1817.13) (2); Distinguished Americans at a Meeting of N-YHS in the Chapel of New York University (2).
  - Negative #20555-20557. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 46, Envelope -)
    Objects: First page of N-YHS Minutes of 1804 (1); Plans of the rooms at the old Alms House (2); New York Hotel (2).
  - Negative #20558-20560. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 48, Envelope -)
    Objects: Seal of N-YHS (1). Buildings: 2nd. Avenue, interior (2)
  - Negative #20561-20566. Glass, 5x7, 1904, Undated (Box 46, Envelope -)
    Buildings: 2nd Avenue interior (2); Central Park West exterior (2), architect York & Sawyer's watercolor (1), groundbreaking (2).
  - Negative #20572. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 48, Envelope -)
    Objects: Drawing of New York's old town hall (1).
  - Negative #20574. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 46, Envelope -)
    Objects: Portrait of John Pintard (2).
  - Negative #20578. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 48, Envelope -)
    Objects: Illustration of Remsen Building (1).
  - Negative #20581. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 46, Envelope -)
    Objects: Isenbrandt Marriage of St. Catherine (2).
  - Negative #20583-20586. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 48, Envelope -)
    Objects: Portrait of Augustus Schell (1); Portrait of Isiah Thomas (1).
  - Negative #20587. Glass, 5x7, 1904 (Box 46, Envelope -)
    Objects: Jean Baptiste Greuze Virginie (object 1867.264) (2).
  - Negative #20588. Glass, 4x5, 1904 (Box 48, Envelope -)
    Object: Illustration of inauguration of George Washington (1).
  - Negative #20589-22690. Film, 5x7, 1949, Undated (Box 49, Envelope -)
    Objects: Wooden water pipes at South Street (1). Buildings: Storage vault plans (1).
  - Negative #22823-22883. Film, 8x10, 1942, Undated (Box 32, Envelope -)
    Galleries and Rooms (7), including World War II precautions. Thompson Homestead Memorial (9). Exhibitions: America Calls (2); Croton Water (3); Jenny Lind (2); Home Crafts and Early Industries of America (2).
  - Negative #23024-23362. Film, 5x7, circa 1940?, 1950, Undated (Box 50, Envelope -)
    Programs and Events: Placing wreath at Simon Bolivar statue (2). Staff (17). Signage (1).
  - Negative #23401-23404. Film, 8x10, 1945 (Box 33, Envelope -)
    Galleries (4).
  - Negative #23678-23731. Film, 5x7, Undated (Box 50, Envelope -)
    Staff (1). Engraved scrolls of appreciation presented by N-YHS (2).
  - Negative #25759-26250. Film, 8x10, 1938-1945, Undated (Box 33, Envelope -)
    Building exterior (1). Programs & Events (3), including Red Cross during WWII. Exhibitions: New York Stage (3); Washington Irving (4); Portraits of Americans (7); Blair collection (2); Allied Artists of America (5); Christmas Cards for Armed Services (1); Christmas Remembrances (6); Latin Americana (3); Jenny Lind. Galleries and Rooms (2).
  - Negative #26913-27894. Film, 5x7, 1944-1947, Undated (Box 50, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Love & Lace Paper/Valentine (6); Men & Ships of the American Navy signage (1); Our GIs in Seven Wars signage (1); News Artists to the American People signage (1); Trinity Church 250th Anniversary (3). Programs and Events: New York Library Club Meeting (3).
  - Negative #27918-28000. Film, 8x10, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Historic Hudson (4); News Artists (7). Staff (2).
  - Negative #28642. Film, 5x7, 1947 (Box 50, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: News Artists to the American People signage (1).
  - Negative #28651-28826. Film, 8x10, 1947, 1964, Undated (Box 33, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: New York City Under the Dutch (1); Crystal Palace (6); Trinity Church (13); William R. Miller Memorial (6); Frederic Remington (8); Golden Anniversary of Greater New York (9). Galleries and Rooms (13). Programs and Events (1).
  - Negative #28882. Film, 5x7, 1946 (Box 50, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: American Silver signage (1).
  - Negative #28883. Film, 8x10, Undated (Box 33, Envelope -)
    Engraving of St. Nicholas (1).
  - Negative #28927-29415. Film, 5x7, 1946-1947, Undated (Box 50, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Doctors of Old New York signage (1); World of Washington Irving signage (1); Audubon: Birds of America signage (2); Jenny Lind signage (1); Historic Hudson signage (2); American Silver signage (1); Amateur Periodicals (1); Trinity Church 250th Anniversary (8); Recent Accessions, 1947 (1); Golden Anniversary of Greater New York (3). Programs and Events: Stuyvesant tercentenary (4). Staff (1).
  - Negative #29435-29899. Film, 5x7, 1947-1948, Undated (Box 51, Envelope -)
    Programs and Events: Presentation of Guildhall-oak gavel to N-YHS (3); Presentation of the bell from the "Elizabeth" (3); Presentation of Atlantic Neptune copper plates (2); Strawberry Festival, 1947 (17); Water main break (6). Exhibitions: Frederic Remington signage (2); Golden Anniversary of Greater New York (1). Staff, behind the scenes shots (4).
  - Negative #29984-29995. Film, 8x10, 1948 (Box 33, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Big Snow (1); George Harvey (6); American Quilts (4).
  - Negative #30030. Film, 5x7, Undated (Box 51, Envelope -)
    Objects: Engraving of N-YHS Meeting at New York University (1).
  - Negative #30157-30290. Film, 8x10, 1947-1948, Undated (Box 33, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: American Quilts (5); Social Life in the 1880s (1) Recent Accessions (1). Views from N-YHS roof (4). Loaned Object: Coach (L 1938.1).
  - Negative #30407-30530. Film, 5x7, 1948 (Box 51, Envelope -)
    Programs and Events: Powder horn demonstration (5); Educational program about 19th century costume and personal effects (5); Strawberry Festival, 1948 (4).
  - Negative #30662-30744. Film, 8x10, 1948-1950 (Box 34, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Stuyvesant Fish Collection (1); 18th Century American Powder Horns (1); Lafayette at Castle Garden (1); Recent Accessions, 1948 (4); Recent Accessions, 1950 (3); Enit Kaufman Show (4); American Book-Printing in the Mauve Quindecad (8). Object: Park drag (1938.386).
  - Negative #30808-30830. Film, 5x7, 1949 (Box 51, Envelope -)
    Programs and Events: Strawberry Festival (24).
  - Negative #30998-31697. Film, 5x7, 1949-1950, Undated (Box 52, Envelope -)
    Objects: Bell from "Clermont" (object 1949.177) (5); Map prepared by Museum Dept (1); Fort George stone marker (2); etching by Ernest D. Roth (1). Exhibitions: Our City Hall in History (7); Garson collection of menus (1). Programs and Events: Presentation of Gramercy Park artifacts (2); montage concerning educational programs (2); Arthur A. Jones memorial (1); Strawberry Festival (31).
  - Negative #32022-32285. Film, 8x10, 1950-1966, Undated (Box 34, Envelope -)
    Galleries and Rooms: Folk Arts (12); American Period Rooms (Prentis?) (12); Early New York (10). Exhibitions: Treasures in Glass (3); Scrimshaw (1); Manhattan Island Milestone (1); Toy exhibit (8); Murphy Collection (8); Vote for Women (4); Hats in the Ring (7); Circus Time (4); Healing Art of Old New York (3); Old Fashioned Winters (1).
  - Negative #32939-33323. Film, 5x7, 1951 (Box 52, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Simon Bolivar (2); Opening of Prentis Collection (20). Programs & Events: Press reception for F. van Wyck Mason book Proud New Flags (4); Gallatin commemoration at Trinity Church (3). Staff: Farewell party for Alexander Wall, Jr (3).
  - Negative #33352-33992. Film, 5x7, 1951 (Box 53, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Survivors of a Century/Newspapers (3); Lloyd Morris's Incredible New York manuscripts (4); Early American Toys (13). Programs and Events: Strawberry Festival (21). Staff Christmas parties (27).
  - Negative #34465-34531. Film, 8x10, 1954-1955, 1963 (Box 34, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: William Sidney Mount (1); American Silver (1); The Society's Treasures signage (1); Silver Lustre Collection (1); Presidents and Statesmen (1); Belknap Discoveries (1). Galleries: Early American Arts & Crafts (12). Strawberry Festival, 1955 (3).
  - Negative #34532-34656. Film, 8x10, 1955-1958, 1963 (Box 35, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Ezra Ames (2); Shircliffe Menu Collection (9); Elevated Railroads (9); New York, Empire State (6); Christmas in New York (6); American Silver (3). Galleries (2). Strawberry Festival (6).
  - Negative #34658-34661. Film, 5x7, 1958 (Box 53, Envelope -)
    Programs and Events: Strawberry Festival (4).
  - Negative #34664-34668. Film, 8x10, 1958 (Box 35, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Daguerreotypes (5).
  - Negative #34669. Film, 5x7, 1958? (Box 53, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Daguerreotypes? (2).
  - Negative #34672-34751. Film, 8x10, 1958-1963 (Box 35, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: American Silver (4); The Hudson River (6); Perry Brothers (1); Niagara Falls (15). Staff (1).
  - Negative #34752. Film, 5x7, 1960 (Box 54, Envelope -)
    Memorial for Bella Landauer (3).
  - Negative #34764-34994. Film, 8x10, 1957-1963 (Box 35, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Early American Household Utensils (4); American Silver (3); Nation Divided (6); Prentis Gallery (2); John Hill (5); Prelude to Civil War (8). Galleries and Rooms (1). Strawberry Festival (2). Signage (1).
  - Negative #35225-35938. Film, 5x7, 1952 (Box 54, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: 150th Anniversary of U.S. Military Academy at West Point (14); 24 Sculptured Portraits of Distinguished Citizens by Malvina Hoffman (6); Hats in the Ring (21). Staff (5). Programs and Events: Party on the S.S. Liberte (13); Strawberry Festival (20).
  - Negative #35939-36963. Film, 5x7, 1952-1953 (Box 55, Envelope -)
    Exhibitions: Hats in the Ring and Votes for Women, including Eleanor Roosevelt speaking at N-YHS (12); Circus Time (19); New York City's 300th Anniversary signage (1); Programs and Events: Strawberry Festival (12); Presentation of Belgian tapestry (8); Visit of Mayor Roger Baudrin (France) (3); Childen's story hour (5); St. Nicholas Festival (13). Staff (2). Memorials (3). N-YHS truck (1).
  - Negative #36964-37523. Film, 5x7, 1952-1954 (Box 56, Envelope -)